Southworth-Dickinson Family Papers, 1792-2005
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES III. DICKINSON FAMILY
  Dwight's correspondence also contains many letters between him and his wife Syria Elana "Sea" Browne, discussing their engagement and wedding and Dwight's work with the navy, including descriptions of Cuba, 1870, and Costa Rica, 1880. Letters from Dwight's son Spencer concern his desire for a new "wheel" [bicycle], 1898; his experiences at Harvard Engineer Camp at Squam Lake, N.H.; and his trip to Nome, Alaska, 1906, while in the navy.
  Mayotta's Dickinson's papers include substantial correspondence between her and her first husband, Arthur, who was writing to her while away at sea. An undated letter of 21 July from Mayotta discusses family picnics at Deer Isle, Me.
- SERIES IV. BROWNE FAMILY
  This series mostly consists of the correspondence of Lucy Mitchell Browne and her children. Included in Lucy's correspondence are letters of 1894 from son J. Mitchell Browne, writing from California, discussing the death of "Lupy," a Native American who died from consumption; railroad strikes; and the "modern young woman." A letter from Nina to Lucy mentions the Keeley treatment for a family member's alcohol abuse. Correspondence between Lucy and daughter Sylvia discusses Sylvia's marriage to Dwight Dickinson, herbal medicine, worker strikes, and Lucy's trip to Deer Isle, Maine, with Joseph Fremont Banks. A letter from Lucy Mitchell Browne to Lucy Serena (Croghan) Browne describes a typhoid outbreak in Oakland, Calif., 1893; and a letter from Spencer Browne to Spencer Dickinson discusses (with illustrations) amusement park rides, 1894.
- SERIES V. DEANE FAMILY
  This series chiefly contains the papers of Rebecca Dennis (Padelford) Deane, her son Melvin, and Melvin's son, John Gilmore. Letters from Rebecca to Melvin discuss family news and include frequent admonitions against Melvin eating poor food and not leading a religious life. John Gilmore Deane's correspondence chiefly concerns his service in the 6th Maine battery as a lieutenant during the Civil War, including description of camp life in the Army of the Potomac and John's participation in the major battles in the East. Letters mention John passing by Robert E. Lee's house in [October?] 1862, conscription in the North, 1863, and the siege at Petersburg, 1864. Also included are two letters not written by John, one from an unknown Confederate soldier writing from Tennessee, 1863, and a letter from a soldier apparently from the 35th U.S. Colored Troops, writing in December 1865 from South Carolina and mentioning "old master."
- SERIES VI. SOUTHWORTH MANUFACTURING COMPANY RECORDS
  This series chiefly contains incoming correspondence from various individuals and paper manufacturers to company founders Wells, his brother Edward, and their cousin John H. Southworth. Also included are many loose financial items, account books, and ledgers concerning daily operation of the company. Correspondence mostly concerns routine financial matters, but also includes discussion of larger political and economic events, such as a letter of 13 February 1844 mentioning the possible election of Henry Clay to the presidency. Also included, in items from 1862-65, is a report on how the Civil War was affecting the paper industry.
  Post-Civil War papers include items about the company as well as correspondence between family members concerning individual financial and estate issues and the Southworth family's claim to lands in Michigan.
- SERIES VII. MISCELLANEOUS MATERIALS
  This series contains miscellaneous correspondence written by and to non-family members, genealogical information, and an unidentified family scrapbook.
- SERIES I. SOUTHWORTH FAMILY
  - Generation 1: Constant Southworth (b. 1730) memoir, typescript and copy of original, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Generation 2
    - Keziah Boltwood Southworth: letter, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Rev. David Thurston
      - Correspondence, 1845-64, undated (Box 1, Folder 3-7)
      - Sermons (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Memorials, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Prudence Brown Thurston: correspondence, 1865-66 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Deborah Haskins Shepard
      - Correspondence, 1836-38 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
      - Portrait (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Generation 3
    - Hannah Shepard Terry
      - Correspondence, 1818-62, undated (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
      - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Thomas Shepard
      - Correspondence, 1845-77 (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
      - Portrait (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Rufus Southworth (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Mary Shepard
      - Correspondence, 1828-63, undated (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
      - Photographs (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - George Champlin Shepard
      - Correspondence, 1828-61 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
      - Photographs (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Will (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Charles Upham Shepard
      - Correspondence, 1828-80, undated (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
      - Miscellaneous writings (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Photograph (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Lucius Boltwood: correspondence and biographical sketches (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Fanny Haskins Boltwood: correspondence and photograph (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Mary Southworth: correspondence, 1850-61, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Wells Southworth: correspondence (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Edward Southworth
      - Biographical materials (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
      - Correspondence
        - A - Butler (Box 4, Folder 4-11)
        - C - L (Box 5, Folder 1-9)
        - M - Southworth, George C. S., 1857-59 (Box 6, Folder 1-19)
        - Southworth, G. C., 1860-69; Southworth, Mary W., 18581858-69 (Box 7, Folder 1-14)
        - Southworth, Mary W., 1860-61 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
        - Southworth, Mase (Box 8, Folder 4-10)
        - Unsigned and undated correspondence (Box 8, Folder 11)
        - Letters of condolence,re: death of Edward Southworth 1869-70 (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
        - Memorials (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Legal and financial materials
        - Miscellaneous items, 1845-63 (Box 9, Folder 1-12)
        - Miscellaneous items, 1864-69, undated (Box 10, Folder 1-11)
        - Stock certificates (Box 11, Folder 1)
        - Deeds and mortgages (Box 11, Folder 2)
        - Andover Seminary Endowment (Box 11, Folder 3)
        - De Forest Estate (Box 11, Folder 4)
        - Thomas A. Perry Estate (Box 11, Folder 5-7)
        - Account books
          - 1829-34 (Box 11, Folder 8-9)
          - 1832-66 (Box 12, Folder 1-5)
        - Estate papers
          - Miscellaneous items, 1870-82, undated (Box 13-14)
          - Account books (Box 15-16)
          - Ledgers (Box 17)
      - Miscellaneous Items
        - Political writings and publications (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
        - Sermons saved by Edward Southworth (Box 18, Folder 3)
        - Advertisements (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Anne E. Shepard Southworth
      - Correspondence, 1820-47, undated (Box 18, Folder 5-7)
      - School notebooks, 1823-27 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Mary W. Shepard Southworth
      - Journal, 1838-45 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Diary, 1843 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Financial items (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Autograph book (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Photographs and miscellaneous items (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Harriet Anne Thurston Deane Southworth
      - Diary and booklets, 1892 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Travel diary, 1901 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence
        - A - Philbrook, Elisabeth, 1841-54 (Box 19, Folder 3-20)
        - Philbrook, Elisabeth, 1855-68, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
        - Philbrook, Ella - Southworth, Ada, 1897-99 (Box 20, Folder 2-14)
        - Ada Southworth, 1900-34, undated (Box 21, Folder 1-4)
        - Alice Southworth, 1872-1902, undated (Box 21, Folder 5-12)
        - Southworth, Alice - Southworth, John D. 1903-08, undated (Box 22, Folder 1-19)
        - Mase Southworth (Box 23, Folder 1)
        - Melvin Deane Southworth (Box 23, Folder 2)
        - Rufus Southworth (Box 23, Folder 3)
        - Thomas Southworth
          - 1876-86 (Box 23, Folder 4-10)
          - 1887-89, undated (Box 24, Folder 1-8)
          - 1890 - Jun 1892 (Box 25, Folder 1-5)
          - Jul 1892 - Dec 1894 (Box 26, Folder 1-5)
          - 1895 - Jun 1899 (Box 27, Folder 1-9)
          - Jul 1899 - 1922, undated (Box 28, Folder 1-9)
        - Virginia Sprague Southworth (Box 28, Folder 10)
        - Sperry - W (Box 29, Folder 1-13)
        - Unknown correspondents (Box 29, Folder 14)
        - Letters from Europe to unknown correspondents, 1899 (Box 29, Folder 15)
      - Financial materials
        - Receipts, 1869-1905 (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
        - Account books
          - 1874-1893 (Box 30, Folder 3-10)
          - 1882-1891 (Box 30A, Folder 1-6)
          - 1898-1907 (Box 31, Folder 1)
        - Estate papers (Box 31, Folder 2-6)
        - Legal papers (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - Album, 1844 (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - Religious writings by Harriet, 1848-63 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Loose scrapbook items (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous items (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Generation 4
    - George C. S. Southworth
      - Biographical information (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Diary, 1870 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence
        - A - Boltwood, Thomas K. (Box 32, Folder 6-10)
        - Boltwood, Tillie - G (Box 33, Folder 1-11)
        - H - P (Box 34, Folder 1-8)
        - R - Southworth, Horatio W. (Box 35, Folder 1-10)
        - Southworth, Jean H. - Southworth, Tom, 1897-98 (Box 36, Folder 1-14)
        - Southworth, Tom, 1899 - Y (Box 37, Folder 1-9)
        - Unsigned, undated, and unknown (Box 37, Folder 10)
        - Letter book, 1870 (Box 38, Folder 1)
        - Outgoing letters record book, 1873-75 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Plans for house alterations (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Misc. writings by George, including A Footprint of Forty-Four, about an enslaved African American (Box 38, Folder 4-6)
      - Financial materials
        - Miscellaneous items
          - 1859-70 (Box 38, Folder 7-8)
          - 1871-1906, undated (Box 39, Folder 1-8)
          - 1907-17 (Box 40, Folder 1)
        - Account books, 1870-76 (Box 40, Folder 2-3)
        - Michigan lands information (Box 40, Folder 4)
        - Estate information, 1918-19 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Ada Southworth
      - Correspondence
        - H - J (Box 40, Folder 6)
        - Alice Southworth, 1872-1906 (Box 40, Folder 7-9)
        - Southworth, Alice - Williams 1907-19 (Box 41, Folder 1-6)
        - Unidentified (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous writings (Box 41, Folder 8)
      - Financial and legal materials
        - Miscellaneous items, 1869-1903, undated (Box 41, Folder 9-12)
        - Miscellaneous items, 1904-08, undated (Box 42, Folder 1-9)
        - Account books, 1874-94 (Box 43, Folder 1-10)
        - Account books, 1890-1904 (Box 44, Folder 1-10)
      - Legal papers, 1926-27 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Estate papers (Box 45, Folder 2-6)
    - Mase Southworth
      - Correspondence and other items (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Account book, 1878 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Dr. Edward Southworth
      - Correspondence and financial items (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Photographs of Italy (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Letters of condolence re: death of Edward, 1882 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Mary Southworth Stevens
      - Correspondence, 1874-1941, undated (Box 46, Folder 4-6)
      - Miscellaneous financial items, 1870-83 (Box 46, Folder 7-8)
    - Dr. Thomas Southworth
      - Biographical information (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence
        - Alice Southworth
          - 1875-1910, undated (Box 46, Folder 10-11)
          - 1911-40, undated (Box 47, Folder 1-7)
        - Hamilton Southworth, 1921-39, undated (Box 47, Folder 8-12)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 47, Folder 13)
      - Financial
        - Miscellaneous items, 1868-77 (Box 47, Folder 14)
        - Miscellaneous items, 1878-82 (Box 48, Folder 1-2)
        - Account books (Box 48, Folder 3-4)
      - Photographs (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Jean Hamilton Southworth
      - Correspondence with Hamilton Southworth
        - 1920-22, undated (Box 48, Folder 6-8)
        - 1923-25, undated (Box 49, Folder 1-4)
      - Receipt, 1883 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Alice Southworth
      - Diaries
        - 1878-27 Sep 1886 (Box 49, Folder 6-10)
        - 1887-1944 (Box 50, Folder 1-8)
      - Correspondence
        - A - B (Box 50, Folder 9-10)
        - C - Harrison, Edward (Box 51, Folder 1-14)
        - Harrison, Elizabeth - J (Box 52, Folder 1-15)
        - K - Southworth, Constant (Box 53, Folder 1-14)
        - Southworth, Rev. Constant W. - Southworth, Mary V. M (Box 54, Folder 1-20)
        - Southworth, Mayotta - V (Box 55, Folder 1-16)
        - W - undated (Box 56, Folder 1-6)
        - Letters to "The Chronicle" (Box 56, Folder 7)
        - Letters concerning Kenneth Alcott, 1900-01 (Box 56, Folder 8)
        - Travel letters, 1899-1900 (Box 56, Folder 9)
      - Financial materials
        - Miscellaneous items (Box 56, Folder 10-11)
        - Account books
          - 1874-1912 (Box 56A, Folder 1-5)
          - 1945-53 (Box 56B, Folder 1-7)
          - 1945-54 (Box 57, Folder 1-2)
        - Estate papers (Box 57, Folder 3-9)
        - Estate papers (Box 58, Folder 1-6)
      - Miscellaneous hand-written writings (Box 58, Folder 7-8)
      - Travel writings
        - Europe trip, 1900 (Box 58, Folder 9)
        - Hawaii trip, 1921-22
          - Notes and writings, including notes on Calif. (Box 59, Folder 1)
          - Journal (Box 59, Folder 2)
          - Brochures and pamphlets (Box 59, Folder 3)
          - Photographs and postcards (Box 59, Folder 4-5)
          - Seashells (Box 60, Folder 1)
          - Souvenirs and miscellaneous (Box 60, Folder 2-5)
          - Passport and visas (Box 60, Folder 6)
      - Sketchbook, undated (Box 60, Folder 7)
      - Notebook, 1895 (Box 60, Folder 8)
      - Notebook, 1932 (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - Address book, 1888 (Box 61, Folder 2)
      - Deer Isle mailing addresses (Box 61, Folder 3)
      - Personal calendar, 1951 (Box 61, Folder 4)
      - Southworth Weekly News,1889 (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Religious writings and publications kept by Alice, 1835-1911 (Box 61, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous writings and publications kept by Alice (Box 61, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous drawings kept by Alice (Box 61, Folder 8)
      - Collection of quotations, compiled by Linda Fitch (Box 61, Folder 9)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box 61, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous advertisements (Box 61, Folder 11)
      - Photographs of Alice (Box 61, Folder 12)
      - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 61, Folder 13)
      - Wallet and lace sample (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - Anna Jenks
      - Correspondence
        - 1883-1897 (Box 62, Folder 1)
        - From Europe1899-1900 (Box 62, Folder 2-3)
        - 1901-1942, undated (Box 62, Folder 4-9)
        - Concerning Kenneth Alcott, undated (Box 62, Folder 10)
        - Anna to Carrie Jenks, undated (Box 62, Folder 11)
        - Miscellaneous letters to Anna Jenks, undated (Box 62, Folder 12)
        - Letters written by Anna Jenks, undated (Box 62, Folder 13)
      - Legal and financial materials, 1936-41 (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Obituaries for friends of Anna and Alice (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Wellesley College book, 1875 (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Address book (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - House specifications, Winter Park, FL, 1940 (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Drawings, undated (Box 63, Folder 6)
      - Photographs (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Jenks Family: miscellaneous
      - Florence Jenks drawing book (Box 63, Folder 8)
      - Student science sketchbook (Box 63, Folder 9)
      - Southern Pines, NC, information (Box 63, Folder 10)
      - Family photographs (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Generation 5
    - Mary Southworth Williams
      - Biographical information (Box 63, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence and other papers (Box 63, Folder 13)
      - Financial and estate papers (Box 63, Folder 14-16)
      - Photographs (Box 63, Folder 17)
    - Constant Southworth
      - Biographical information (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Camp book, 1892-94 (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, 1895-1924 (Box 64, Folder 3-5)
      - World War I materials
        - Diary, 1917-19 (Box 64, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence, 1916-19 (Box 64, Folder 7-9)
        - Training camp booklets and memoranda (Box 64, Folder 10)
        - Loose scrapbook pages (Box 64, Folder 11-15)
        - Loose scrapbook pages (Box 65, Folder 1-4)
        - Bound books of photographs, 332nd Infantry Regiment (Box 65, Folder 6)
        - Photographs matted on paper (Box 66, Folder 1-4)
        - Loose photographs (Box 66, Folder 5-7)
        - Oversize photographs (Box 66, Folder 8)
        - Rolled-up panoramic photographs, 332nd Regiment (Box 67, Folder 1-5)
        - Negatives (Box 68, Folder 1)
        - Postcards (Box 68, Folder 2)
        - Writings by Constant Southworth (Box 68, Box 3-4)
        - Writings kept by Constant (Box 68, Folder 5-9)
        - Badges and medals (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - Childhood writings (Box 69, Folder 2)
      - Kenyon College papers (Box 69, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous writings by Constant, including items concerning Woodrow Wilson, U.S. foreign policy, lynching, and divorce (Box 69, Folder 4-5)
      - Miscellaneous poetry kept by Constant (Box 69, Folder 6)
      - Death and memorials (Box 70, Folder 1-3)
      - Estate papers (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - Masonic certificate and medals (Box 70, Folder 5)
      - Oversize legal certificates (Box 70, Folder 6)
      - Wallets (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Rufus Southworth
      - World War I diary: typed carbon copy (Box 71, Folder 1)
      - World War I letters: typed carbon copies (Box 71, Folder 2)
      - Letters from the ship The Yankee, typed carbons1933-34 (Box 71, Folder 3)
      - Letters from Pitcairn Island, typed carbons 1937 (Box 71, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 1939-40 (Box 71, Folder 5)
      - Photographs (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Elizabeth Shepard Southworth Harrison
      - Correspondence (Box 71, Folder 7)
      - Photographs (Box 71, Folder 8-9)
    - Melvin Deane Southworth
      - Biographical information (Box 72, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1901-67 (Box 72, Folder 2-8)
      - Travel log, 1933 (Box 72, Folder 9)
      - Account book, 1903-25 (Box 72, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous financial items (Box 72, Folder 11)
      - Ruth Doris Swett Estate (Melvin Southworth executor) (Box 73, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous writings kept by Melvin (Box 73, Folder 2)
      - Memberships, associations, and professional information (Box 73, Folder 3)
      - Reality Club papers (Box 73, Folder 4)
      - Loose scrapbook pages, 1900s-1960s, undated (Box 73, Folder 5-11)
      - Bound scrapbooks
        - 1907-09 (Box 73, Folder 12)
        - 1946-47 (Box 74, Folder 1)
      - Pamphlets, programs, and souvenirs (Box 74, Folder 2)
      - Memorials (Box 74, Folder 3)
      - Estate (Box 74, Folder 4)
      - Photographs (Box 74, Folder 5)
      - Wallet (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Edward and Virginia Sprague Southworth (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - George S. Southworth
      - Correspondence (Box 74, Folder 8)
      - Writings on Mexico trip, 1959,and Hawaii trip, 19621959, 1962 (Box 74, Folder 9)
      - Memoirs, undated (Box 74, Folder 10)
      - Photographs (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Sue F. Williams Southworth: correspondence (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - John D. Southworth
      - Biographical information (Box 75, Folder 2)
      - World War I materials
        - Diary: typed carbon copy (Box 75, Folder 3)
        - Letters: typed carbon copies (Box 75, Folder 4)
        - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 75, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1923-45 (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - Generation 6
    - Dr. Hamilton Southworth
      - Childhood writings (Box 75, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence and other papers (Box 75, Folder 8)
      - School records (Box 75, Folder 9)
      - Photographs and negatives (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Edward Southworth (1907-2001): memorials (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Elizabeth Southworth Corning (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Constant W. Southworth (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Edward Woodberry Southworth (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Ann Southworth Frost (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Southworth Warner (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Helen Southworth Atwood (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Mayotta Southworth Kendrick (Box 76, Folder 8-12)
    - Edmund H. Kendrick (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Howard Corning: obituary (Box 76, Folder 14)
- SERIES II. "THE CHRONICLE"
  - Constant Southworth letters from Europe, 1899-1900 (Box 77)
  - Family letters, 1908 (Box 78)
  - Constant Southworth letters from Alaska, 1909 (Box 79)
  - Melvin Deane Southworth letters from Europe, 1909-10 (Box 80)
  - Family letters and papers
    - 1909 (Box 81)
    - 1910 (Box 82)
    - 1911 (Box 83)
    - 1912 (Box 84)
    - 1913 (Box 85)
    - 1914 (Box 86)
    - 1915 (Box 87)
    - 1916 (Box 88)
    - 1917 (Box 89)
    - 1918 (Box 90)
    - 1919 (Box 91)
    - 1920-21 (Box 92)
    - 1922-23 (Box 93)
    - 1924-25 (Box 94)
    - 1926-28 (Box 95)
    - 1929-30 (Box 96)
    - 1931-32 (Box 97)
    - 1933-35 (Box 98)
  - Rufus Southworth letters, "Yankee World Cruise," 1933-35 (Box 99)
  - Family letters
    - 1936-37 (Box 100)
    - 1938-39 (Box 101)
    - 1940 (Box 102)
    - 1941-47 (Box 103)
- SERIES III: DICKINSON FAMILY
  - Generation 1
    - Edward A. Dickinson
      - Biographical information (Box 104, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence (Box 104, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous writings (Box 104, Folder 3-6)
    - Sarah Maria Fletcher Dickinson
      - Correspondence, 1843-62 (Box 104, Folder 7)
      - Letter book, circa 1836 (Box 104, Folder 8)
      - Album: poems and messages from friends, 1837 (Box 104, Folder 9)
      - Seminary [Mt. Holyoke College] papers, 1841-42 (Box 104, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous writings, 1840-71, undated (Box 104, Folder 11)
    - Sarah Maria Dickinson memoir by Lucy Hawley, undated (Box 104, Folder 12)
  - Generation 2
    - Dr. Dwight Dickinson
      - Biographical information, 1859-1970 (Box 104, Folder 13)
      - Diaries
        - 1866, 1878 (Box 104, Folder 14)
        - 1880-93 (Box 105, Folder 1-6)
        - 1894-1904 (Box 106, Folder 1-5)
        - 1905-13 (Box 107, Folder 1-6)
        - 1914-20 (Box 108, Folder 1-7)
        - 1921-25 (Box 109, Folder 1-5)
        - 1926-28 (Box 110, Folder 1-3)
      - Correspondence
        - A - Dickinson, Edward F., 1857-79 (Box 110, Folder 4-8)
        - Edward F. Dickinson (b. 1849), 1880-99, undated (Box 111, Folder 1-4)
        - Edward F. Dickinson (b. 1890) (Box 111, Folder 5)
        - J. M. Dickinson (Box 111, Folder 6)
        - Syria "Sea" Dickinson
          - 1881-86 (Box 111, Folder 7-12)
          - 1887 - Jun 1894 (Box 112, Folder 1-12)
          - Jul 1894-99, undated (Box 113, Folder 1-12)
        - Dickinson, Sarah - Z (Box 114, Folder 1-6)
        - Unsigned and undated (Box 114, Folder 7)
      - Naval papers (Box 114, Folder 8-9)
      - Miscellaneous writings (Box 114, Folder 10)
    - Sylvia Elana Browne Dickinson: correspondence, 1869-99, undated (Box 114, Folder 11-13)
    - Edward F. Dickinson (Box 114, Folder 14)
    - Sarah E. Dickinson
      - Diary, 1918-25 (Box 115, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1880-1926 (Box 115, Folder 2)
      - Wellesley College materials
        - Miscellaneous papers and writings (Box 115, Folder 3)
        - Notebooks, 1878-83, undated (Box 115, Folder 4-8)
        - Yearbook, 1902 (Box 115, Folder 9)
        - Illustrated booklet, "Reminiscences," undated (Box 116, Folder 1)
        - Miscellany (Box 116, Folder 2)
      - Obituaries (Box 116, Folder 3)
      - Photographs (Box 116, Folder 4)
  - Generation 3